<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Todd Davies&#39; Website</title>
    <link>https://todddavi.es/</link>
    <description>Read the latest on Todd Davies&#39; Website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>todd@todddavi.es (Todd Davies)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>todd@todddavi.es (Todd Davies)</webMaster><atom:link href="https://todddavi.es/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://todddavi.es/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>todd@todddavi.es (Todd Davies)</author>
      <guid>https://todddavi.es/about/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m a PhD candidate in Law at University College London. My research asks how competition law can understand market competition as a process, drawing from theoretical ecology and systems theory to do so. I work as a graduate lecturer at the UCL Laws, where I also run the Law and Political Economy Group.
I hold a master&amp;rsquo;s degree in Politics and Technology from the Technical University Munich and a bachelor&amp;rsquo;s degree in Computer Science from The University of Manchester.</description>
      <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[ <p>I&rsquo;m a PhD candidate in Law at <a href="https://www.ucl.ac.uk/laws/">University College
London</a>. My research asks how competition law can understand market competition as a process, drawing from theoretical ecology and systems theory to do so. I work as a graduate lecturer at the <a href="https://www.ucl.ac.uk/laws/ucl-faculty-laws">UCL Laws</a>, where I also run the <a href="https://sites.google.com/view/ucl-lpe/home">Law and Political Economy Group</a>.</p>
<p>I hold a master&rsquo;s degree in <a href="https://www.tum.de/en/studies/degree-programs/detail/politics-technology-master-of-science-msc">Politics and
Technology</a>
from the <a href="https://www.tum.de/en/">Technical University Munich</a> and a
bachelor&rsquo;s degree in <a href="https://www.cs.manchester.ac.uk/">Computer
Science</a> from <a href="https://www.manchester.ac.uk">The University of
Manchester</a>. I previously worked for six years as a software engineer at <a href="https://google.com">Google</a>, mostly in the security and privacy space.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;m interested in topics which ultimately impact human
flourishing. In particular, virtue ethics and how social technologies can be a force for good in an age of metacrisis (surpassed planetary boundaries, increasing inequality, geopolitical strife, existential risk production, etc). Here is a <a href="/beliefs">list of things I believe</a>. Here is a <a href="/cities">list of cities I visited</a> with recommendations and photos.</p>
 ]]>
      </content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cities</title>
      <link>https://todddavi.es/cities/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>todd@todddavi.es (Todd Davies)</author>
      <guid>https://todddavi.es/cities/</guid>
      <description>Here is a list of things I like in a bunch of cities that I&amp;rsquo;ve visited. I&amp;rsquo;m slowly migrating content from a bunch of Google Docs pages, so more will appear here over time. Feel free to contact me if something is outdated or incorrect. Food recommendations are likely vegan.
 Amsterdam Rome  </description>
      <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[ <p>Here is a list of things I like in a bunch of cities that I&rsquo;ve visited. I&rsquo;m slowly migrating content from a bunch of Google Docs pages, so more will appear here over time. Feel free to contact me if something is outdated or incorrect. Food recommendations are likely vegan.</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="/travel/amsterdam/">Amsterdam</a></li>
<li><a href="/travel/rome/">Rome</a></li>
</ul>
 ]]>
      </content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes (archived)</title>
      <link>https://todddavi.es/notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>todd@todddavi.es (Todd Davies)</author>
      <guid>https://todddavi.es/notes/</guid>
      <description>I used to post my school/university notes on here. I no-longer do because most of them are horrifically out of date. If you&amp;rsquo;re interested, you&amp;rsquo;re welcome to look directly at the Git repos, which have the compiled pdf files in them.
 B.Sc Computer Science Year 3 B.Sc Computer Science Year 2 B.Sc Computer Science Year 1 A-level GCSE  FYI posting my notes online was probably the most rewarding and useful thing I did during my bachelor&amp;rsquo;s degree.</description>
      <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[ <p>I used to post my school/university notes on here. I no-longer do because most of them are horrifically out of date. If you&rsquo;re interested, you&rsquo;re welcome to look directly at the Git repos, which have the compiled pdf files in them.</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/Todd-Davies/third-year-notes">B.Sc Computer Science Year 3</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/Todd-Davies/second-year-notes">B.Sc Computer Science Year 2</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/Todd-Davies/first-year-notes">B.Sc Computer Science Year 1</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/Todd-Davies/A-Level-Notes">A-level</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/Todd-Davies/GCSE-Notes">GCSE</a></li>
</ul>
<p>FYI posting my notes online was probably the most rewarding and useful thing I did during my bachelor&rsquo;s degree. If you&rsquo;re considering it, I strongly recommend it. If you have any questions, feel free to <a href="mailto:todd@todddavi.es">email me</a>.</p>
 ]]>
      </content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on Amsterdam</title>
      <link>https://todddavi.es/travel/amsterdam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>todd@todddavi.es (Todd Davies)</author>
      <guid>https://todddavi.es/travel/amsterdam/</guid>
      <description>Status: Incomplete, I need to visit more!
Food  TerraZen is a Caribbean &amp;amp; Japanese fusion place. It&amp;rsquo;s all vegan, good value and delicious. Men Impossible is a vegan ramen place. They have a five(!) course meal for 59 euros, which although on the expensive side for a meal, is an absolute steal for what you get. They have one big table in the middle of the restaurant, around which everybody sits.</description>
      <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[ <p><strong>Status</strong>: Incomplete, I need to visit more!</p>
<h1 id="food">Food</h1>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://maps.app.goo.gl/3U98DJmXPBdSVWux7">TerraZen</a> is a Caribbean &amp; Japanese fusion place. It&rsquo;s all vegan, good value and delicious.</li>
<li><a href="https://maps.app.goo.gl/j5M966S5safZ9ztx6">Men Impossible</a> is a vegan ramen place. They have a five(!) course meal for 59 euros, which although on the expensive side for a meal, is an absolute steal for what you get. They have one big table in the middle of the restaurant, around which everybody sits.</li>
<li><a href="https://maps.app.goo.gl/cZBQGpgnhCCeMpCK9">Margo&rsquo;s</a> is a delicious (vegan) bakery with a large selection of sweet and savoury things. They also do top notch coffee and other drinks.</li>
<li><a href="https://maps.app.goo.gl/KjWpd1RcavpZYQzo9">FEBO</a> is on the list for novelty rather than quality. It&rsquo;s a fast food place where the food is pre-prepared and served by a vending machine style setup. No vegan options (I think?), but it&rsquo;s fun to try.</li>
</ul>
<h1 id="fun">Fun</h1>
<ul>
<li>Walk around the <a href="https://maps.app.goo.gl/zyJXuYmWCCeLrjzE9">Jordaan</a> district. I think it&rsquo;s the best part of Amsterdam; lots of canals, food options, good shops, etc.</li>
<li><a href="https://maps.app.goo.gl/UN24HZn3hEJMt4Tg6">Wynand Fockink</a> is a historic liquour store. They have a quite unique set-up where the bartender will help you figure out which (combinations) of their very large selection of flavours to try.</li>
<li><a href="https://maps.app.goo.gl/98em8SXcrmBgDFM28">Vondelpark</a> is worth a visit, if the weather is good.</li>
<li><a href="https://maps.app.goo.gl/8kr56LsT3cVL5FJ6A">Melkweg</a> is a good club in Amsterdam.  They have lockers, food etc.</li>
<li>Rather than taking a canal tour, consider the free 15 minute ferry between <a href="https://maps.app.goo.gl/zBxa3DaZornQRSzt7">Amsterdam Central</a> and <a href="https://maps.app.goo.gl/eksdV3z6gGkvwZYq7">NDSM</a>. When you arrive, there&rsquo;s a beachside restaurant/bar <a href="https://maps.app.goo.gl/UywjDK3Uh78ops6Z8">here</a>.</li>
</ul>
<h1 id="nearby">Nearby</h1>
<p>The Netherlands has fantastic trains. It&rsquo;s a breeze to visit plenty of nearby cities which are amazing in their own right, including Delft, Leiden, Utrecht, etc.</p>
<h1 id="photos">Photos</h1>
<p>
<img class="enclosure" src="/cities/amsterdam.jpg" alt="A photo I took of three people waving from a boat on a canal in Amsterdam."  />
</p>
 ]]>
      </content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on Rome</title>
      <link>https://todddavi.es/travel/rome/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>todd@todddavi.es (Todd Davies)</author>
      <guid>https://todddavi.es/travel/rome/</guid>
      <description>Status: Incomplete, I need to visit more!
Food  Maritozzo is kind of like a Roman sandwich. It’s traditional Roman food, so maybe worth a try while you’re in town. You can find some here. Negresco Ristorante Pizzeria have lovely staff and make delicious food. They were incredibly nice, and I ended up eating for free! El Maìz does delicious Venezuelan street food! They are 100% gluten free (because everything is corn) and have vegan options.</description>
      <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[ <p><strong>Status</strong>: Incomplete, I need to visit more!</p>
<h1 id="food">Food</h1>
<ul>
<li>Maritozzo is kind of like a Roman sandwich. It’s traditional Roman food, so maybe worth a try while you’re in town. You can find some <a href="https://maps.app.goo.gl/zFfm99hVk1EvFTfJ9">here</a>.</li>
<li><a href="https://maps.app.goo.gl/aXFDzkCtLo4ksXDk6">Negresco Ristorante Pizzeria</a> have lovely staff and make delicious food. They were incredibly nice, and I ended up eating for free!</li>
<li><a href="https://maps.app.goo.gl/2rrg2NGm9NPo3EKLA">El Maìz</a> does delicious Venezuelan street food! They are 100% gluten free (because everything is corn) and have vegan options.</li>
</ul>
<h1 id="fun">Fun</h1>
<ul>
<li>The <a href="https://maps.app.goo.gl/t1F5Y3ozm8gt87CQ8">Pantheon</a> is amazing. I&rsquo;ve not yet managed to get inside, though not for lack of trying (&hellip;you should buy tickets online).</li>
<li><a href="https://maps.app.goo.gl/zcG4aEMx65g3oMK49">Galleria Alberto Sordi</a> is a very aesthetic shopping centre (the shops are closed for renovation as of 2023 but you can still look inside).</li>
<li><a href="https://maps.app.goo.gl/JmFPaHs37331N4J5A">Borghese Gallery</a> houses many of the most famous artworks in Rome.</li>
<li><a href="https://maps.app.goo.gl/EpN9YNVJnQJsDJi6A">Castel Sant&rsquo;Angelo</a> is a fortress which started out as a mausoleum. Again, I&rsquo;ve not yet been in, but would love to go!</li>
<li>The <a href="https://maps.app.goo.gl/dWgNQpe5VrZUSnaH7">Vatican/St. Peter&rsquo;s Basilica</a> is obviously worth a visit (although I also didn&rsquo;t go in, as of yet).
Parks</li>
<li><a href="https://maps.app.goo.gl/QBSaqapoU3t2TCvy6">Villa Borghese</a> is a really pretty park with lots of busts of famous Italians which is fun to look around. The Borghese gallery is also here.</li>
</ul>
<h1 id="nearby">Nearby</h1>
<ul>
<li>It&rsquo;s just one hour on the train to <a href="/cities/napoli/">Napoli</a>!</li>
</ul>
<h1 id="photos">Photos</h1>
<p>
<img class="enclosure" src="/cities/rome.jpg" alt="A photo I took of three people waving from a boat on a canal in Amsterdam."  />
</p>
<p>
<img class="enclosure" src="/cities/rome_2.jpg" alt="A photo I took of three people waving from a boat on a canal in Amsterdam."  />
</p>
<p>
<img class="enclosure" src="/cities/rome_3.jpg" alt="A photo I took of three people waving from a boat on a canal in Amsterdam."  />
</p>
<p>
<img class="enclosure" src="/cities/rome_4.jpg" alt="A photo I took of three people waving from a boat on a canal in Amsterdam."  />
</p>
 ]]>
      </content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some Things I Believe</title>
      <link>https://todddavi.es/beliefs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>todd@todddavi.es (Todd Davies)</author>
      <guid>https://todddavi.es/beliefs/</guid>
      <description>Here are some things that I believe about how to live, in no particular order.
 Enthusiasm matters  Doing great work requires motivation. It&amp;rsquo;s easier to be motivated when you like something. Things become more enjoyable when you get good at them.   We should aim for significant things  We only get one life. It&amp;rsquo;s better to use it on significant things, rather than to &amp;ldquo;muddle through&amp;rdquo;. You can still enjoy something, even if you ultimately fail.</description>
      <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[ <p>Here are some things that I believe about how to live, in no particular order.</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://nat.org/">Enthusiasm matters</a>
<ul>
<li>Doing great work requires motivation.</li>
<li>It&rsquo;s easier to be motivated when you like something.</li>
<li>Things become more enjoyable when you get good at them.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/530415.The_Art_of_Doing_Science_and_Engineering">We should aim for significant things</a>
<ul>
<li>We only get one life.</li>
<li>It&rsquo;s better to use it on significant things, rather than to &ldquo;muddle through&rdquo;.</li>
<li>You can still enjoy something, even if you ultimately fail.</li>
<li>You get to define what is significant.</li>
<li>If you&rsquo;re stuck, aim for <a href="https://www.google.com/search?q=Max+Scheler+pyramid+of+values&amp;tbm=isch">&lsquo;sacred&rsquo; over &lsquo;utility&rsquo;</a>.</li>
<li>Success is mostly about perspiration and luck. Luck favours the prepared mind.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>It&rsquo;s smart to align yourself with the public interest
<ul>
<li>Your own interest is important.</li>
<li>But it has diminishing returns.</li>
<li>You can align your private interest with the public interest.</li>
<li>The public interest has increasing returns, and more potential for signficance.</li>
<li>It feels good to work on something larger than yourself.</li>
<li>Don&rsquo;t underestimate your capacity to change the world!</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/en/book/show/29568959">Self examination is important</a>
<ul>
<li>It&rsquo;s possible to critically assess your own thought patterns.</li>
<li>This lets you improve how you think.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/en/book/show/3828902">Everything is a system</a>
<ul>
<li>The direct cause of a problem is sometimes misleading.</li>
<li>Look for the underlying systemic issues and their downstream effects.e</li>
<li>Challenges and responses &gt; problems and solutions.</li>
<li>Look to think synergistically across domains when responding to challenges.</li>
<li>This is where magic happens.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="https://nat.org/">Speed is important</a>
<ul>
<li>You learn via receiving feedback from your actions.</li>
<li>The quicker you execute, the more feedback you&rsquo;ll generate.</li>
<li>This is why we learn quickly while playing; there&rsquo;s usually a rapid feedback loop.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/97412.On_the_Shortness_of_Life">Wisdom only correlates with age</a>
<ul>
<li>Wisdom comes from distilling knowledge out of experience.</li>
<li>Experience correlates with age.</li>
<li>But it&rsquo;s possible to live essentially the same year many times.</li>
<li>Each &lsquo;repeated&rsquo; experience is likely to generate less feedback, and less wisdom.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="https://twitter.com/startingfromnix/status/1607763222303756290">Self discipline is delayed gratification</a>
<ul>
<li>Delaying gratification is a form of self love.</li>
<li>You must care enough for your future self to sacrifice your present self.</li>
<li>Delayed gratifiation can be an end almost in itself.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/97412.On_the_Shortness_of_Life">The Good Life is for now</a>
<ul>
<li>On the other hand, putting things off is a trap; we might never get to them.</li>
<li>Nevertheless, you can be content in a surprising number of circumstances.</li>
<li>You get to decide what the good life looks like.</li>
<li>Pay <a href="https://lithub.com/simone-weils-radical-conception-of-attention/">attention</a> to what matters.</li>
<li>There are several ways to train your attention. Meditation is a good one.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/13470.Think_on_These_Things">Competition is dangerous for individuals</a>
<ul>
<li>Competition is great for honing a specific task.</li>
<li>But there are relatively few winners and many more losers.</li>
<li>Losing a competition can entail a high opportunity cost.</li>
<li>The world is big and weird.</li>
<li>There are many tasks that need doing in the world.</li>
<li><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/en/book/show/18050143">Develop a unique bundle of skills. Excel at them.</a></li>
<li>These skills define your niche.</li>
<li>A small enough niche has no competition, so you&rsquo;re always a winner.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Competition is good for groups
<ul>
<li>Competition is great for honing a specific task.</li>
<li>The world is big and weird.</li>
<li>There are many tasks that need doing in the world.</li>
<li>Competition is a great way to figure out how to do them well.</li>
<li>Winners experience positive feedback and are likely to win again.</li>
<li>Competitions need counterveiling negative feedback loops to run indefinitely.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/530415.The_Art_of_Doing_Science_and_Engineering">Compound returns isn&rsquo;t just for money</a>
<ul>
<li>Compound returns works on relationships, skills, knowledge, etc.</li>
<li>For example, it&rsquo;s easier to learn something if you already know related things.</li>
<li>Invest early, and often!</li>
<li>Most investments will make modest returns, some will give huge ones.</li>
<li>Play long term games with long term people.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/43566091-lessons-in-stoicism">We should focus on what we can control</a>
<ul>
<li>The only things we can truly control are our thoughts and actions.</li>
<li>We can&rsquo;t even control what happens to our bodies. For example, we can get sick.</li>
<li>Focus on what you can control, avoid worrying about what you can&rsquo;t.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/13470.Think_on_These_Things">An intelligent mind is an inquiring mind</a>
<ul>
<li>Our minds can only model the world.</li>
<li>Models are necessarily incomplete.</li>
<li>We should resist being satisfied with our conclusions.</li>
<li>We can watch, study, learn, and be ready to <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/5550.Perfectly_Reasonable_Deviations_from_the_Beaten_Track">irreverently</a> throw out ideas when they&rsquo;re wrong.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4kBoLVvoqVY">The world is in a state of metacrisis</a>
<ul>
<li>Metacrisis is the idea that humanity faces a set of overlapping and interlinked crises.</li>
<li>These crises may have discrete causes, but their production is systemic.</li>
<li>Working our way out of the metacrisis is a defining challenge of my generation.</li>
<li>Nihilism is bad.</li>
<li>Dedicate yourself to finding ways to thrive instead.</li>
<li>Again, if you&rsquo;re stuck, aim for <a href="https://consilienceproject.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/TRANSCRIPT_-The-Psychological-Drivers-of-the-Metacrisis.pdf">&lsquo;sacred&rsquo; over &lsquo;utility&rsquo;</a>.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p>Comments? Get in touch via <a href="mailto:todd@todddavi.es">email</a> or <a href="https://www.admonymous.co/daviest">anonymously</a>.</p>
<p>Inspired by <a href="https://nat.org/">Nat Friedman</a>, <a href="http://invece.org/">Salvatore Sanfilippo</a> and others.</p>
 ]]>
      </content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
