<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Todd Davies&#39; Website</title>
    <link>https://todddavi.es/</link>
    <description>Read the latest on Todd Davies&#39; Website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>todd@todddavi.es (Todd Davies)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>todd@todddavi.es (Todd Davies)</webMaster><atom:link href="https://todddavi.es/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://todddavi.es/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>todd@todddavi.es (Todd Davies)</author>
      <guid>https://todddavi.es/about/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m a PhD candidate in Law at University College London. My research draws from ecology and evolutionary economics to ask how competition law can understand market competition as a process. I work as a graduate lecturer at the UCL Laws, where I also run the Law and Political Economy Group.
I hold a master&amp;rsquo;s degree in Politics and Technology from the Technical University Munich and a bachelor&amp;rsquo;s degree in Computer Science from The University of Manchester.</description>
      <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[ <p>I&rsquo;m a PhD candidate in Law at <a href="https://www.ucl.ac.uk/laws/">University College
London</a>. My research draws from ecology and evolutionary economics to ask how competition law can understand market competition as a process. I work as a graduate lecturer at the <a href="https://www.ucl.ac.uk/laws/ucl-faculty-laws">UCL Laws</a>, where I also run the <a href="https://sites.google.com/view/ucl-lpe/home">Law and Political Economy Group</a>.</p>
<p>I hold a master&rsquo;s degree in <a href="https://www.tum.de/en/studies/degree-programs/detail/politics-technology-master-of-science-msc">Politics and
Technology</a>
from the <a href="https://www.tum.de/en/">Technical University Munich</a> and a
bachelor&rsquo;s degree in <a href="https://www.cs.manchester.ac.uk/">Computer
Science</a> from <a href="https://www.manchester.ac.uk">The University of
Manchester</a>. I previously worked for six years as a software engineer at <a href="https://google.com">Google</a>, mostly in the security and privacy space.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;m interested in topics which ultimately impact human
flourishing. In particular, virtue ethics and how social technologies can be a force for good in an age of metacrisis (surpassed planetary boundaries, increasing inequality, geopolitical strife, existential risk production, etc).</p>
 ]]>
      </content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some Things I Believe</title>
      <link>https://todddavi.es/posts/beliefs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>todd@todddavi.es (Todd Davies)</author>
      <guid>https://todddavi.es/posts/beliefs/</guid>
      <description>Here is some stuff I believe, in no particular order.
 Work on stuff you like  Doing great work requires motivation. It&amp;rsquo;s easier to be motivated when you like something. Things become more enjoyable when you get good at them.   We should aim for great things  We only get one life. It&amp;rsquo;s better to use it on significant things, rather than to &amp;ldquo;muddle through&amp;rdquo;. You can still enjoy something, even if you ultimately fail.</description>
      <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[ <p>Here is some stuff I believe, in no particular order.</p>
<ul>
<li>Work on stuff you like
<ul>
<li>Doing great work requires motivation.</li>
<li>It&rsquo;s easier to be motivated when you like something.</li>
<li>Things become more enjoyable when you get good at them.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/530415.The_Art_of_Doing_Science_and_Engineering">We should aim for great things</a>
<ul>
<li>We only get one life.</li>
<li>It&rsquo;s better to use it on significant things, rather than to &ldquo;muddle through&rdquo;.</li>
<li>You can still enjoy something, even if you ultimately fail.</li>
<li>Success is mostly about perspiration and luck. Luck favours the prepared mind.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Align yourself with the public interest
<ul>
<li>Your own interest is important.</li>
<li>But it has diminishing returns.</li>
<li>You can align your private interest with the public interest.</li>
<li>Working in the public interest has a higher ceiling.</li>
<li>Don&rsquo;t underestimate your capacity to change the world!</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="/reflexive-self-examination">We should think reflexively</a>
<ul>
<li>It&rsquo;s possible to critically assess your own thought patterns.</li>
<li>This lets you improve how you think, and become a better person.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/en/book/show/3828902">Think in systems</a>
<ul>
<li>Problems often don&rsquo;t have a direct cause.</li>
<li>They have several or many interlocking causes.</li>
<li>Challenges and responses &gt; problems and solutions.</li>
<li>Look to think synergistically across domains when responding to challenges.</li>
<li>This is where magic happens.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Speed is important
<ul>
<li>You learn via receiving feedback from your actions.</li>
<li>The quicker you execute, the more feedback you&rsquo;ll generate.</li>
<li>This is why we learn quickly while playing; there&rsquo;s usually a rapid feedback loop.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="https://twitter.com/startingfromnix/status/1607763222303756290">Self discipline is delayed gratification</a>
<ul>
<li>Delaying gratification is a form of self love.</li>
<li>You must care enough for your future self to sacrifice your present self.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/13470.Think_on_These_Things">Avoid competition with others</a>
<ul>
<li>Competition is great for honing a specific task.</li>
<li>But the world is big and weird.</li>
<li>There are many tasks we can do and roles we can play.</li>
<li>Pick a unique bundle of skills.</li>
<li>Excel at providing those skills to the world.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/530415.The_Art_of_Doing_Science_and_Engineering">Compound returns isn&rsquo;t just for money</a>
<ul>
<li>Compound returns works on relationships, skills, knowledge, etc.</li>
<li>For example, it&rsquo;s easier to learn something if you already know related things.</li>
<li>Invest early, and often!</li>
<li>Most investments will make modest returns, some will give huge ones.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/43566091-lessons-in-stoicism">We should focus on what we can control</a>
<ul>
<li>The only thing we can truly control is our thoughts and actions.</li>
<li>We can&rsquo;t even control our bodies. For example, we can get sick.</li>
<li>Focus on what you can control, avoid worrying about what you can&rsquo;t.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/97412.On_the_Shortness_of_Life">Don&rsquo;t put off the good life</a>
<ul>
<li>Putting things off is a trap; we might never get to them.</li>
<li>You can be content in a surprising number of circumstances.</li>
<li>You get to decide what the good life looks like.</li>
<li>Pay <a href="https://lithub.com/simone-weils-radical-conception-of-attention/">attention</a> to what matters.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/97412.On_the_Shortness_of_Life">Wisdom only correlates with age</a>
<ul>
<li>Wisdom comes from distilling knowledge out of experience.</li>
<li>Experience correlates with age.</li>
<li>But it&rsquo;s possible to live essentially the same year many times.</li>
<li>It&rsquo;s also possible to exist, but to not really live.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/13470.Think_on_These_Things">An intelligent mind is an inquiring mind</a>
<ul>
<li>Our minds can only model the world.</li>
<li>Models are always wrong, and always incomplete.</li>
<li>We should resist being satisfied with our conclusions.</li>
<li>We can watch, study, learn, and be ready to throw out our ideas when they&rsquo;re wrong.</li>
<li>&ldquo;<a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/5550.Perfectly_Reasonable_Deviations_from_the_Beaten_Track">Study what interests [you] in the most irreverent, undisciplined and original manner possible</a>&rdquo;.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4kBoLVvoqVY">The world is in a state of metacrisis</a>
<ul>
<li>Metacrisis is the idea that humanity faces a set of overlapping and interlinked crises.</li>
<li>These crises may have discrete causes, but their production is systemic.</li>
<li>Working our way out of the metacrisis is a defining challenge of my generation.</li>
<li>Nihilism is bad.</li>
<li>Choose to thrive instead.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p>Comments? Get in touch via <a href="mailto:todd@todddavi.es">email</a> or <a href="https://www.admonymous.co/daviest">anonymously</a>.</p>
<p>Inspired by <a href="https://nat.org/">Nat Friedman</a>.</p>
 ]]>
      </content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
