<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Todd Davies</title>
    <link>https://todddavi.es/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Todd Davies</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2020 10:57:03 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://todddavi.es/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>https://todddavi.es/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 12:11:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://todddavi.es/research/</guid>
      <description>My research focuses on the intersection between economic competition, complex systems, and the law. In particular, I&#39;m interested in how the structure of markets and the actions of individual agents combine to create emergent behaviour.
Ongoing projects  Computing Competition with Agent-Based Models (2021, in-progress) This paper applies techniques from complexity science to competition law. I build an agent-based model to simulate zero-price markets. Using the model, I investigate the dynamics of these markets, and the effect of policy remedies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hamming Art Science Engineering</title>
      <link>https://todddavi.es/blog/hamming-art-science-engineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 13:08:58 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://todddavi.es/blog/hamming-art-science-engineering/</guid>
      <description>The Art of Doing Science and Engineering by Richard Hamming (Amazon, Goodreads) is an excellent book. It distills a career of scientific research and engineering practice into a series of focused chapters, each with a specific theme.
Some of the examples of views are a little outdated, but this is principally because Hamming did his work in the mid-20th century. While a lot has changed since then, it is testament to his skill and good-opinions that most of what he wrote is still valuable now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Technology That Works</title>
      <link>https://todddavi.es/blog/new-technology-that-works/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2020 21:25:41 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://todddavi.es/blog/new-technology-that-works/</guid>
      <description>Technology is supposed to improve our lives by solving problems that we face every day, but doesn&amp;rsquo;t always live up to its promises. This post discusses how the reMarkable v2 tablet is a device that delivers on technology&amp;rsquo;s promises.

The reMarkable in action, with my todo list on it
As a political science student, a typical week&amp;rsquo;s work includes reading about five academic papers. The papers are usually interesting and selected by course leaders for their high quality and relevance, but since starting my degree over a year ago, I often found that while I enjoyed the content of what I was reading, the process of reading itself wasn&amp;rsquo;t so great.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uk Cop 2020</title>
      <link>https://todddavi.es/blog/uk-cop-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2020 21:24:13 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://todddavi.es/blog/uk-cop-2020/</guid>
      <description>This is an open letter to Boris Johnson, highlighting the importance of the UK&amp;rsquo;s presidency of the United Nations&#39; conference on climate change in 2020.
Dear Prime Minister,
I have a vision for the future; where foreign conflicts are solved without losing soldiers, disease is overcome before it becomes a pandemic and climate change is avoided while our economy simultaneously thrives. Where countries work together to overcome the many challenges we face across a global landscape; , addressing problems of a size and scale way beyond the capabilities of an individual nation state.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Stuff Down</title>
      <link>https://todddavi.es/blog/getting-stuff-down/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 21:20:52 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://todddavi.es/blog/getting-stuff-down/</guid>
      <description>My life got more busy lately since I started a masters degree, perhaps it&amp;rsquo;s not the best time to start a blog. But, as the headmaster at my high school would cheekily remark, &amp;ldquo;if you want something doing, give it to a busy person&amp;rdquo; (often at the end of a conversation to parents about homework allocation).
In order to make the blog successful, it needs to have content. I think if I try to make each new post as good as I can, then this blog will remain decidedly empty.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Pull</title>
      <link>https://todddavi.es/blog/how-to-pull/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2019 16:24:32 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://todddavi.es/blog/how-to-pull/</guid>
      <description>If you want to skip to the tutorial, click here.
Soon after starting at university, I started to become frustrated with the rather poor quality of the lecture slides we would have to revise from. Though all the information was there, and it was (mostly) perfectly clear if you attended all the lectures, when it came to revising for the exams, it was hard to figure out what exactly was happening from the lecture slides themselves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Starting a Blog</title>
      <link>https://todddavi.es/blog/starting-a-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2019 16:22:21 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://todddavi.es/blog/starting-a-blog/</guid>
      <description>The internet has gotten a lot of flak recently for facilitating information pollution via the World Wide Web, which is a shame, since the internet is also an incredible force for good in the world.
I recently realised how much I love looking at what people produce online. It&amp;rsquo;s easy for me to spend lots of time looking at aggregated content on Hacker News and Lobste.rs, in part, because it&amp;rsquo;s rich in stuff that represents the best of the web; highly heterogeneous content from individual creators who are passionate about what they&amp;rsquo;re doing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes</title>
      <link>https://todddavi.es/notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://todddavi.es/notes/</guid>
      <description>Here are most of the notes that I made while studying for various exams. I&#39;m currently studying for a masters degree in Politics and Technology, and my notes should appear here when I&#39;ve finished courses.
Previous notes from my GCSE, A-level and Bachelors level examinations are here too. Please double check all information in them whilst revising, there&#39;s no guarantee that they are correct.
Politics and Technology  Name Course code Download   Introduction to Politics and Technology  POL40100 pdf  Climate Politics Term Paper: Environmental governance in the corporate sector of the United States  POL23300 pdf  Comparative Politics: Fundamentals (flashcards)  POL10500 pdf  Comparative Politics: Fundamentals  POL10500 pdf  Politics for Rocket Scientists  POL00011 pdf  Emerging Technologies and International Security Literature Review: Conceptualizations of 5G  POL61305 pdf  Emerging Technologies and International Security Literature Review: Hybrid Warfare Tactics  POL61305 pdf   BSc Computer Science (third year)  Name Course code Download   Advanced Algorithms I  COMP36111 pdf, kindle  AI &amp;amp; Games  COMP34120 pdf, kindle  Natural Language Systems  COMP34411 pdf, kindle  Compilers  COMP36512 pdf, kindle  Advanced Algorithms II  COMP36212 pdf, kindle  Chip Multiprocessors  COMP35112 pdf, kindle   BSc Computer Science (second year)  Name Course code Download   Databases  COMP23111 pdf, kindle  Operating Systems  COMP25111 pdf, kindle  Algorithms and Imperative Programming; Semester I  COMP26121 pdf, kindle  Machine Learning  COMP24111 pdf, kindle  System Architecture  COMP25212 pdf, kindle  Algorithms &amp;amp; Imperative Programming; Semester II  COMP26212 pdf, kindle  Distributed Computing  COMP28112 pdf, kindle  Mobile Systems  COMP28512 pdf, kindle  Software Engineering Semester 1 Flashcards  COMP23421 pdf  An Introduction to Current Topics in Biology Flashcards  UCOL20882 pdf   BSc Computer Science (first year)  Name Course code Download   Fundamentals of Computer Architecture  COMP15111 pdf, kindle  Mathematical Techniques for Computer Science; Semester I  COMP11120 pdf, kindle  Fundamentals of Distributed Systems Flashcards  COMP18112 pdf  Fundamentals of Computation  COMP11212 pdf, kindle  Fundamentals of Computer Engineering  COMP12111 pdf, kindle  Mathematical Techniques for Computer Science; Semester II  COMP11120 pdf, kindle  Fundamentals of Artificial Intelligence Flashcards  COMP14112 pdf   A-level  Name Course code Download   Mechanics 1 (M1)  M1 pdf  Core 4 (C4); Intergration  C4 pdf  A-Level Biology  BIOL(2|4|5) zip  A-Level Physics  G48(2|4|5) zip   GCSE  Name Course code Download   GCSE Geography; Human Geography  9030 docx  GCSE Chemistry 3  4402 docx  GCSE Physics 3  4403 docx  GCSE Design Technology; Electronic Products  4540 docx  GCSE Information Technology and Communication  ICT docx  GCSE Biology 3  4401 docx   </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
